Finding Aid for the Yuji Ichioka Papers LSC.0242
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Publications
  - Ganbatte
    - Material pertaining to Yoneda's life and political activism (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Research Material (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Research Material (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Draft of Ichioka's Introduction, ca. 1982-1983 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Edited Version of Karl Yoneda's Autobiography, Part I, June 1982 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Edited Version of Karl Yoneda's Autobiography, Part II, June 1982 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Final Manuscript, Part I, ca. 1983 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Final Manuscript, Part II, ca. 1983 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Karl G. Yoneda, Ganbatte (1983), with flier and book reviews (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Original draft of Yoneda's Autobiography, Part I, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - "Revised Manuscript" (Extended Version) of "Ganbatte", Part I, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - "Ganbatte," Part II, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Japanese Version of Ganbatte (1984) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - The Issei
    Scope and Contents note
    Yuji Ichioka, The Issei: The World of the First Generation Japanese Immigrants, 1885-1924 (New York: Free Press, 1988).
    - Working Draft: "Student-Laborers," "Prostitutes and Pimps-Gamblers," "Laborers" (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Working Draft: "Chapter Three" (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Working Draft: "Workers' Daily Life" (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Working Draft: "Labor Organizing" (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Working Draft: "Draft to be Revised" (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Working Draft: "Shikatsu Mondai--Extended Version" (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Book Manuscript (First Version): Chapters I and II (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Book Manuscript (First Version): Chapters III and IV (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Book Manuscript (First Version): Chapters V and VI (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Book Manuscript (First Version): Chapters VI and VII (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Research Memos and Notes for Revision (First Version) (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - "Aliens Ineligible to Citizenship," Chapters I-III (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - "Aliens Ineligible to Citizenship," Chapters IV-V (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - "Aliens Ineligible to Citizenship," Chapters VI-VII (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - "The Issei" (Copyedited Version), Front Matter, and Chapters I-III (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - "The Issei" (Copyedited Version), Chapters IV-V (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - "The Issei" (Copyedited Version), Chapters VI (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "The Issei" (Copyedited Version), Chapter VII, Notes, and Bibliography (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Yuji Ichioka, The Issei (1988) (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Marked-up Japanese translation of the Issei (second half only) (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Marketing fliers (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Copyedited endnotes and Ichioka's letter to Kodansha International., January 1987 (Box 146, Folder 7)
      (See also Box 26, Folders 1-3.)
    - Book reviews and prizes for The Issei, including marketing materials., 1988-1989 (Box 153, Folder 1-2)
      (See also Box 27.)
    - The Issei book promotion talks and community lectures., 1988-1989 (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - Book reviews for the Japanese-version of The Issei, including letters from ???? Tomita Torao. (Box 153, Folder 4)
  - Yuji Ichioka and Emma Gee, "Asians"
    - Boyd & Fraser Publishing Company Book contract., May 1979 (Never published). (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - Before Internment
    Yuji Ichioka (Gordon H. Chang and Eiichiro Azuma, eds), Before Internment: Essays in Prewar Japanese American History (Stanford: Stanford University Press, 2006).
    - Before Internment marked-up manuscripts (reviewed and copyedited by Emma Gee)., ca. 2004 (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Before Internment marked-up manuscripts (reviewed and copyedited by Emma Gee)., ca. 2004 (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Before Internment marked-up manuscripts (reviewed and copyedited by Emma Gee)., ca. 2004 (Box 146, Folder 10)
  - Articles
    - "The Turlock Incident: Economic Competition and Racism," draft., 1976 (Box 147, Folder 1)
      (See also Box 30, Folder 2.)
    - "Ameyuki-san: Japanese Prostitutes in the 19th Century America," draft with research notes., August 1976 (Box 147, Folder 2)
      (See also Box 30, Folder 8.)
    - "Asian Immigrant Coal Miners and the United Mine Workers of America: Race and Class at Rock Springs, Wyoming, 1907," 2 copies of final draft with reviews from anonymous referees and friends., 1978 (Box 147, Folder 3)
      (See also Box 31, Folders 4-5.)
    - "Japanese Labor Diplomacy: Suzuki Bunji, the American Federation of Labor, and Japanese Exclusion, 1915-1916," draft with Jerry Suh's critique., 1978 (Box 147, Folder 4)
      (See also Box 31, Folders 6-7.)
    - "A Nisei Critique of Futatsu no Sokoku," multiple versions of draft., 1984 (Box 147, Folder 5)
      (See also Box 32, Folder 6.)
    - "The Second Generation Problem," draft., No date (Box 147, Folder 6)
      (See also Box 33, Folders 6-34; and Box 34, Folders 1-4.)
    - "'Unity Within Diversity': Louis Adamic and Japanese Americans," draft and published article., 1986-1987 (Box 147, Folder 7)
      (See also Box 35, Folder 1.)
    - "Kengakudan: The Origin of Nisei Study Tours of Japan," drafts and page proofs: and a galley of the Japanese version, ?????????????????, ca. 1992-1994 (Box 147, Folder 8)
      (See also Box 35, Folder 2.)
    - "Consul Ohashi Chuichi and Japanese Language Schools," drafts., No date (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - "What Matter of Man?: A Portrait of Abiko Kyutaro Through Selected Letters," draft and marked-up page proofs., 1994 (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - "Beyond the Pale: Buddy Kazumaro Uno and the Question of Loyalty in Japanese American History," draft, 1995: and "The Meaning of Loyalty: The Case of Buddy Kazumaro Uno," drafts., 1996 (Box 147, Folder 11)
      (See also Box 35, Folder 4.)
    - "'American Atrocities': The Japan Broadcasting Corporation and the Wartime Internment of Japanese-Americans," draft and outlines., No date (Box 147, Folder 12)
    - Photocopies of published articles: "Japanese Immigrant Labor Contractors and the Northern Pacific and the Great Northern Railroad Companies, 1898-1907," Labor History 21:3 (1980): 326-350; "Early Issei Socialists and the Japanese Community"; and "Abiko Kyutaro: Eiju wo shusho shita Nichibei Shinbun keieisha" [Abiko Kyutaro: the owner of Nichibei Shinbun who advocated permanent settlement], (1984) (Box 147, Folder 13, Folder 1)
      (See also Box 31, Folder 1; and Box 32, Folders 7-8.)
- Research Materials
  - "Dai-Nisei Mondai"
    - Research notes on Nisei education and the second-generation problem (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Shin Sekai Japanese editorials on Nisei education, 1908-1914 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Shin Sekai Japanese editorials on Nisei education, 1915-1920 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Shin Sekai Japanese editorials on Nisei education, 1921-1924 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Immigrant newspaper clippings on Nisei education and other aspects of "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1929-1938 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Clippings of immigrant newspapers on Nisei's dual nationality question, 1910- 1923 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - The Japanese Association of North America, "Kokuseki Ridatsusha Shimei," 1918- 1924 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Seinen, no. 1, 3 (1926-1927) (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Papers relating to Myles Yutaka Fukunaga, 1928 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Japanese-language publications on "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1930s (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Japanese magazine articles on "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1930s (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Japanese magazine articles on "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1930s (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Japanese magazine articles on "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1930s (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - English articles on Nisei education and the foreign language school laws, 1920s (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Japanese consular reports on Japanese language schools in California, 1921- 1923 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Nisei's Japanese compositions, 1938 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Japanese police report on Nisei in Tokyo, 1933 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Tsunemitsu Konen, Nihon Ryugaku no Jissai (1936) (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Yamashita Soen, Nichibei wo tsunagu mono (1938), pp. 1-211 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Yamashita Soen, Nichibei wo tsunagu mono (1938), pp. 212-483 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Aoyagi Ikutaro, Jihenka Zaigai Nihonjin no Tenbo (1940) (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Nippon to Amerika articles on "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1935-1941 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Japanese consular reports on "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1934-1935 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Japanese consular reports on "Dai-Nisei Mondai," 1934-1935 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Japanese consular reports on Nisei's dual nationality problem, 1936 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Japanese consular reports relating to the Japanese oratorical and essay contests, 1933- 1934 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Japanese Foreign Ministry publications on the state of Nisei in North America, 1936- 1937, 1940 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Yamada Tatsumi, Kaigai Dai-Nisei Mondai (1936) (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to the controversy surrounding ôhashi Chûichi ???? "Dôhô Kokugo Gakkô hantairon" ??????????? Shin Sekai ??????, May 24-May 28, 1925 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings relating to the controversy surrounding Oka Naoki ??? "Dai-Nisei no Kyoiku mondai" ?????????? Shin Sekai ??????, July 29-August 14, 1928 (Box 148, Folder 3)
      with English translations by Seizo Oka.
    - Miscellaneous materials relating to the education of the second-generation Japanese Americans., 1926-1930s (Box 148, Folder 4)
  - Abiko Kyutaro and Yonako
    - Materials pertaining to Abiko Kyutaro and Yonako (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Abiko Kyutaro biographical and family materials (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Research materials pertaining to Abiko Kyutaro (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Yamato Colony, and the American Land and Produce Company, 1906-1908 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Nichibei Shimbun articles on Nisei Kengakudan, 1925-1927 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Clippings of miscallaneous newspapers on Nisei Kengakudan in Japan, 1926- 1927 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Copies of Letters from Abiko Yonako, Yaeko Flora Tsuda, and Hisako Fujii, ca. 1925- 1926 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Materials pertaining to Nisei Kengakudan members (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Kengakudan itineraries and miscellaneous items (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Secondary sources on Abiko Kyutaro (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Agriculture
    - Hokubei Noho, no. 5, 7-8 (1910) (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Hokubei Noho, no. 9, 10 (1910) (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Hokubei Noho, vol. 2, no. 1-3 (1911) (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Hokubei Noho, vol. 2, no. 4-6 (1911) (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Shin Sekai clippings on farming and Kashu Chuo Nokai, 1913-1919 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Shin Sekai clippings on farming, 1920-1921, 1926, 1931 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Kawashimo Nogyo Domeikai, Annual report (1909); and the Japanese Farmers in California (1918) (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Japanese consular reports relating to Yokohama Species Bank loans to Issei farmers, 1913-1914 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Japanese consular reports on the 1913 Alien Land Law and Issei reactions, 1913- 1914 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Japanese consular reports on Issei agriculture under the threat of the alien land law, 1914-1915 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Papers relating to Japanese Association of America efforts to amend the 1913 Alien Land Law, 1919 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Japanese consular reports on Issei farming in California, 4 items, 1921-1922 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Japanese consular reports on the alien land law test cases and their aftermaths, 1921- 1923 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Research notes relating to farming and alien land law test cases (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Rafu Shimpo clippings relating to alien land law test cases, 1923 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Legal papers pertaining to State of California v. A. P. Fujita, et al., 1929 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Consular reports on the aftermath of the 1923 U.S. Supreme Court ruling, 1923- 1924 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - "Honpojin Nokosha to no Jokyo ni kansuru Chosasho," Part I, September 1926 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - "Honpojin Nokosha to no Jokyo ni kansuru Chosasho," Part II, December 1926 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - "Ippan Hojin Nogyo Gaikan," October 1926 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Consular dispatches relating to the remigration of Issei farmers to other states, July 1920 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Japanese newspaper clippings relating to the remigration of Issei farmers from the U.S., 1923-1924 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Papers relating to Chiba Toyoji (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Chiba Toyoji's writings, 1920-1922 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Chiba Toyoji's writings, 1925-1932 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Nanka Nogyo Kumiai, Warera no Rekishi (1932) (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Japanese immigrant agricultural statistics, 1905-1920 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - English sources and studies on Japanese immigrant farming (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Statistical and demographic records relating to Japanese immigrant landowners in California, 1913 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Materials relating to the financial crisis of Central California Japanese farmers and the Yokohama Specie Bank., 1917, 1924 (Box 153, Folder 7)
      (See also Box 64, Folders 4, 8).
    - Photocopies of Kashû Chûô Nôkai Geppô ?????????? ?Monthly Report of the Japanese Agricultural Association of California?., April 1916-November 1918. (Box 153, Folder 8)
  - American Intelligence Files
    - FBI, "General Japanese Intelligence Survey in the Los Angeles Division," May 1, 1941 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - FBI, "General Intelligence Surveys," January 1941; and MID, "Japanese Organizations and Societies" (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - ONI, "An Analysis of the Japanese Espionage Problem"; and "Japanese Undercover Organization" (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Papers relating to American intelligence policies, 1941 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Papers relating to suspected Japanese agents and informants, 1938-1944 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Lists of subversive Japanese organizations and firms in the United States, and reports (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Papers relating to the Central Japanese Association of America (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Papers relating to "Heimusha Kai" and "Sokoku Kai" (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Papers relating to Japanese language schools, "State Shinto," and "Butokukai" (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Papers relating to the "Overseas Japanese Central Society" (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - FBI file on Naka Nakane, 1940 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - FBI and ONI reports on Charles H. Yoshii, 1933, 1943-1944 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - FBI reports on Marguerite Smith; Shiro Fujioka; Koshiro Endo; Kohei Shimano; and Nobumichi Ukai (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - FBI, "Japanism and Japanese in the United States," September 1943, pp. 1- 196 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - FBI, "Japanism and Japanese in the United States," September 1943, pp. 197- 333 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Kenneth D. Ringle, "The Japanese Question in the United States," ca. 1942 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - ONI, "Analysis of the Loyalty of Japanese"; and "A Manual for the Evaluation of Japanese Cases" (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Papers relating to military clearance program (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Papers relating to the treatment of Americans by the Japanese, and United States policies (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Early Issei Socialists
    - Materials relating to Kashu Nihonjin Kutsuko Domeikai and Takano Fusataro, 1894- 1899 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Shin Sekai clippings relating to Nihonjin Enko Domei strike, 1900 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Printed materials relating to Katayama Sen (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Copies of Heimin, edited by Katayama Sen, 1916-1919 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Materials relating to Shakai Kakumeisha, 1909-1912 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Reports on Japanese socialists and anarchists in America (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Reports, histories, and correspondence relating to Issei socialists in the early 20th century (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Otsuka Zentaro, Hi-Shakai Shugi (1911) (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Ohara Satoshi's studies of early Issei socialists, 4 items (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Early Students and Political Exiles
    - Research notes relating to the Gospel Society in San Francisco (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Imaizumi Genkichi, Senku Kyujunen (1942) (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Papers relating to Baba Tatsui (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Papers relating to politically active Issei (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Research notes on "dekasegi shosei" (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - English writings relating to student-laborers (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Special issues of Nichibei Shimbun and Shin Sekai relating to student-laborers and early Christians (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Nihonjin articles relating to student-laborers (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Ajiya articles relating to student-laborers (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Articles relating to student-laborers published in Tokyo Keizai Zasshi and Kokumin no Tomo (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Ofu Inshi, Zaibei Seiko no Nihonjin (1904) (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Photocopies of Shin Nihon (1887); Dai-Nihon (1889); and Jiyu (1890) (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Photocopies of Dai Jukyu Seiki (1888-1889, 1893) (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Photocopies of Aikoku (1892) (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Transcriptions of Dai Nihon (1889), and Dai Jukyu Seiki (1888-1889, 1893) (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Transcriptions of Jiyu (1890), and Aikoku (April-June 1892) (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Transcriptions of Aikoku (June-September 1892) (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Lists of early Issei newspapers and their content descriptions (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Research notes and miscellaneous materials on early immigrant newspapers (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy of "Fukuinkai shiryô: Niki no bu (B)" ????????????(B) ?Historical documents of the Gospel Society; Second phase (B)?., October 1887-December 1889. (Box 153, Folder 9)
      (See also Box 56, Folder 8.)
    - Washizu Shakuma ???? "Wagahai no Beikoku seikatsu" ????????? ?Early days of my American life?. 1924-1925. A series of essays published in Nichibei Shimbun, Undated. (Box 154, Folder 1)
      (See also Box 78, Folder 3.)
    - Series of Nichibei Shimbun ?????? essays by Washizu Shakuma????and Yamanaka Chûji ???? on early Issei., 1924-1925 (Box 154, Folder 2)
  - Emigration
    - Ishikawa Tomonori's essays on Japanese emigration studies (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Ishikawa Tomonori's studies of emigration from Okinawa (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Ishikawa Tomonori's studies of emigration from Okinawa (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Ishikawa Tomonori's studies of emigration from Okinawa (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous studies of emigration from Okinawa (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Ishikawa Tomonori's studies of emigration from Hiroshima and Yamaguchi (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Kodama Masaaki's studies of emigration from Hiroshima (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Kodama Masaaki's studies of emigration from Hiroshima (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Kodama Masaaki's studies of emigration from Hiroshima (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Essays and research notes on emigration from Wakayama (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Essays on emigration from Okinawa, Yamaguchi, and Kagoshima (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - English readings of village and town names in Japan (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - English readings of village and town names in Japan (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Wakayama-ken, Wakayama-ken Iminshi vol. 1 (1957) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Wakayama-ken, Wakayama-ken Iminshi vol. 2 (1957) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Wakayama-ken, Wakayama-ken Iminshi vol. 3 (1957) (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Study of an "emigrant village" in Shiga (1964) (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Yoshida Hideo's articles on dekasegi labor migration to Hawaii (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Essays on emigration from Okinawa and Hiroshima (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - General studies of emigration (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Yuji Ichioka's tallies and notes on Japanese emigration statistics (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Nihon Tokei Nenkan statistical data (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Fujii Sei
    - FBI file (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Fujii Sei-shi Sakebu (1931) (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Kashu Mainichi editorials, August 22-September 29, 1938; July 8-August 23, 1952 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Fujii Sei (Oversize)
    - Clippings of Fujii Sei, "Watashi no ran," Kashu Mainichi, 1937 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Guides to Work and Study in America
    - Kaigai Kugaku Annai (1904); Beikoku Ima Fushigi (1886); and Tobei Rashin (1904) (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Kitare Nihonjin (1887) (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Tobei Annai (1901); Zoku Tobei Annai (1902); and Hokubei Jigyo Annai (1906) (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Beikoku Kugaku Jikki (1911) (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Tobei Annai (1901); Beikoku Rodo Binran (1903) (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Beikoku iki Hitori Annai Kahen (1886); notes from Tobei no Shiori (1901) (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Kaigai Risshin no Tebiki (1902) (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Seinen no Tobei (1902); Tobei Seigyo no Tebiki (1903) (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Honda Rikita and Nanka Teikoku Gun`yudan
    - FBI file on Honda Rikita, 1941 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Materials relating to the dealth of Honda Rikita, December 1941 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - FBI reports on Nanka Teikoku Gun`yudan, 1941 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - FBI reports on Nanka Teikoku Gun`yudan, 1941-1942 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - FBI reports on Nanka Teikoku Gun`yudan, 1943 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Research materials relating to members of Nanka Teikoku Gun`yudan (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Justice Department investigative files on members of Nanka Teikoku Gun`yudan (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Military Intelligence reports on Nanka Teikoku Gun`yudan and other Issei veterans organizations (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Photographs (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Ichihashi Yamato
    - FBI file (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - ONI, Military Intelligence, and CIA files (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Japanese Foreign Ministry file regarding Ichihashi's employment at Stanford University, 1913-1914 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Japanese Foreign Ministry file regarding Ichihashi's employment at Stanford University, 1915-1919 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Biographical material, wartime diaries, and miscellanies (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Stanford University colleagues, 1907-1945 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Published articles (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Immigrant Nationalism
    - Clippings of Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1937 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Clippings of Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1938 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Clippings of Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1939 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Clippings of Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1940 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Clippings of Shin Sekai editorials and articles, 1941 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and notes of Nichibei Shimbun editorials and articles, March 1937-June 1938 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and notes of Nichibei Shimbun editorials and articles, July 1938-February 1941 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Clippings of Taihoku Nippo editorials and articles, 1937-1941 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Kashu Mainichi clippings and notes, July 1937-June 1941 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Papers pertaining to political lecturers from Japan, 1937-1938 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Nakamura Kaju, Sekai wo Aruku (1937); and "What Americans Say of Kaju Nakamura's Lectures" (1938) (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Nakamura Kaju, Hokubei Shita no Seisen (1940) (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Fukuda Yoshiaki's Nichibei Shimbun report concerning his trip to Manchuria, February- March 1939 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous materials relating to Japanese immigrant nationalism (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Consular dispatch relating to Japanese organizations in Seattle and their patriotic activities, 1939 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Japanese magazine articles relating to Issei and Nisei, 1920s-1930s (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings and notes relating to Kaigai Doho Tokyo Taikai, November 1940 (Box 73, Folder 3)